{
  "origins": [
    {
      "id": 1,
      "question": "What island is considered the Principle Island of the Ryukyu Archipelago?",
      "options": ["Japan", "Okinawa", "China", "India"],
      "correctAnswer": "Okinawa",
      "selectedAnswer": null
    },
    {
      "id": 2,
      "question": "Who is believed to have brought Chuan-Fa to the Shaolin temple in China during the Sung Dynasty?",
      "options": ["Gichin Funakoshi", "Bodhidharma", "Sakugawa Shungo", "King Satto"],
      "correctAnswer": "Bodhidharma",
      "selectedAnswer": null
    },
    {
      "id": 3,
      "question": "What event in 1609 led to the development of a fighting method known as 'Te' (hand)?",
      "options": [
        "Japanese Satsuma Clan's march on the Ryukyu Islands",
        "Declaration of allegiance by King Satto",
        "Ban on all weaponry",
        "Development of Chuan-Fa in Okinawa"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Japanese Satsuma Clan's march on the Ryukyu Islands",
      "selectedAnswer": null
    },
    {
      "id": 4,
      "question": "Who is commonly known as the father of modern-day karate?",
      "options": ["Bodhidharma", "King Satto", "Gichin Funakoshi", "Sakugawa Shungo"],
      "correctAnswer": "Gichin Funakoshi",
      "selectedAnswer": null
    },
    {
      "id": 5,
      "question": "Which virtue of Bushido emphasizes the importance of treating others with courtesy and consideration?",
      "options": [
        "Righteousness (義 gi)",
        "Loyalty (忠義 chūgi)",
        "Respect (礼儀 reigi)",
        "Courage (勇気 yūki)"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Respect (礼儀 reigi)",
      "selectedAnswer": null
    }
  ],
  "elements": [
    {
      "id": 6,
      "question": "What are the three basic Elements of good Karate?",
      "options": [
        "Ki, Ka, Ku",
        "Kata, Kihon, Kumite",
        "Stance, Strike, Kick",
        "Punch, Block, Spar"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Kata, Kihon, Kumite",
      "selectedAnswer": null
    },
    {
      "id": 7,
      "question": "Which Element of Karate is often considered the Spirit of Karate?",
      "options": ["Kihon", "Kata", "Kumite", "None of the above"],
      "correctAnswer": "Kumite",
      "selectedAnswer": null
    },
    {
      "id": 8,
      "question": "What is the purpose of practicing Kihon in Karate training?",
      "options": [
        "To simulate fights against imaginary opponents",
        "To develop strategy and mental fortitude",
        "To establish a solid foundation and proper technique",
        "To refine form and technique"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "To establish a solid foundation and proper technique",
      "selectedAnswer": null
    },
    {
      "id": 9,
      "question": "What are Kata in the context of Karate?",
      "options": [
        "Basic techniques and principles",
        "Prearranged sequences of movements and techniques",
        "Controlled and supervised combat between two practitioners",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Prearranged sequences of movements and techniques",
      "selectedAnswer": null
    },
    {
      "id": 10,
      "question": "Which of the following is true about Kumite in Karate",
      "options": [
        "It is often performed in a specific pattern",
        "It emphasizes preserving traditional techniques",
        "It involves controlled and supervised combat between two practitioners",
        "It is primarily focused on refining form and technique"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "It involves controlled and supervised combat between two practitioners",
      "selectedAnswer": null
    }
  ],
  "stances": [
    {
      "id": 11,
      "question": "What is the weight distribution for the Zenkutsu-dachi (Front stance)?",
      "options": [
        "50% on front leg, 50% on back leg",
        "30% on front leg, 70% on back leg",
        "70% on front leg, 30% on back leg",
        "90% on front leg, 10% on back leg"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "70% on front leg, 30% on back leg",
      "selectedAnswer": null
    },
    {
      "id": 12,
      "question": "Which stance is the most technically challenging and hardest to master in Shotokan karate?",
      "options": [
        "Kiba-dachi (Horse riding stance)",
        "Heiko dachi (Parallel stance)",
        "Fudo-dachi or Sochin Dachi (Immovable stance)",
        "Kokustu-dachi (Back stance)"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Kokustu-dachi (Back stance)",
      "selectedAnswer": null
    },
    {
      "id": 13,
      "question": "What is the stance used in Shotokan karate kata Sochin, combining half front stance and half horse riding stance?",
      "options": [
        "Kiba-dachi (Horse riding stance)",
        "Heiko dachi (Parallel stance)",
        "Fudo-dachi or Sochin Dachi (Immovable stance)",
        "Zenkutsu-dachi (Front stance)"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Fudo-dachi or Sochin Dachi (Immovable stance)",
      "selectedAnswer": null
    },
    {
      "id": 14,
      "question": "In which stance are the feet placed together, side by side, and the heels together with toes turned out at roughly 45 degrees?",
      "options": ["Kokustu-dachi", "Musubi-dachi", "Heiko dachi ", "Heisoku-dachi"],
      "correctAnswer": "Musubi-dachi",
      "selectedAnswer": null
    },
    {
      "id": 15,
      "question": "What is the weight distribution for Heisoku-dachi (Feet Together Stance)",
      "options": [
        "50% on each leg",
        "70% on one leg, 30% on the other leg",
        "Weight is central",
        "90% on one leg, 10% on the other leg"
      ],
      "correctAnswer": "Weight is central",
      "selectedAnswer": null
    }
  ]
}
